■ +91-9611333500 ■ VinitKr28@gmail.com IIII linkedin.com/in/vinitkr Opgithub.com/vinitkr28 ♦ VinitKr28

#### Summary:

A results-driven, customer-focused, articulate Senior Engineer who can think "out of the box". Strong in design and integration of problem-solving skills. Having 12+ years of overall experience in Android, Java, Kotlin, Flutter, Data Structure, Database and leading Android team with 6 to 8 Mobile App Developers.

#### Experienced In:

Language/Framework/SDK Ex	kperience(Approx)	Last Used
Android Application Development using Android SDK with NDK	10+ year	Current
Kotlin, Coroutines, Kotlin Flow	5 years	Current
<ul> <li>Jetpack compose, Material3</li> </ul>	2 year	Current
Flutter, Dart	3 year	Current
• iOS, Swift 5	1 year	Current
<ul> <li>Xamarin Forms using C#, Visual Studio, React Native</li> </ul>	6 months	Dec 2019
<ul> <li>Video Calling library WebRTC, <u>Frozenmountain</u></li> </ul>	1.5 year	Aug 2020
<ul> <li>Jenkins, Espresso, JUnit, Mockito, LeakCanary, Jacoco, sonarqube, coverity</li> </ul>	7 year	Current
• Firebase(Crashlytics, Analytics, Authentication, Storage, Messaging, Firestore)	7 year	Current
• SQLite, ROOM, JSON, XML	6 year	Current
<ul> <li>Retrofit, Volley, Dagger, MVVM, RxJava &amp; RxAndroid</li> </ul>	7 year	Current
<ul> <li>Android app for voice-based <u>Realwear(hmt-1, 1Z1)</u> hand's free device</li> </ul>	2 year	Aug 2020
<ul> <li>Google Exoplayer (Android video streaming library), Amazon LEX</li> </ul>	1.5 year	June 2019
Mobile app wireframe designing	1 year	April 2019
<ul> <li>Google Map, Place API, GPS, aGPS, Fused location</li> </ul>	3 year	2018
<ul> <li>Javascript, JQuery, Kendo UI</li> </ul>	1 year	2015
SIP, AChartEngine	1 year	2014
• Servlet, Struts 1.0, J2EE, Tomcat, mySQL, Oracle database	3 year	2015

#### **Employment:**

Devel	lopmer	าt Eng	ineer

Signify Innovation India Limited, Bangalore Formerly known as "Philips Lighting India Limited"	Sep 2020 - Present
Software Engineer II, Honeywell Technology Solutions Lab Pvt Ltd, Bangalore	Aug 2016 - Sep 2020
Senior Engineer, Tata Elxsi Pvt Ltd, Bangalore	Feb 2015 - July 2016
Senior Development Engineer, Pixel Softek Pvt Ltd, Bangalore	Nov 2011 - Jan 2015

#### Award & Achievement:

Project Excellence Awards, Tata Elxsi	June 2015
Bronze Award, Honeywell, 2nd Position - Hackathon conducted by Honeywell	Nov 2017, Jan 2018
Scaled Agile, Certified SAFe 5 Practitioner	February 2023
HTS PMT HOS India Annual Award for 2017	February 2018
Bronze Award, Honeywell	Feb 2019 & July 2019
Certificate of Appreciation, Signify	Feb 2021, Jan 2023

### Internship & Training:

Tavant Technology, Bangalore	June 2009 - July 2009
Corporate Java Training Form Java Learning Centre, Bangalore	May 2010 - Oct 2010
Udemy Android Unit Testing and Test Driven Dev   Udemy Certificate Link	November 2020

### **Education:**

Master of Technology(M-Tech) in Computer Science And Engineering

#### **Project in Company:**

# Project 1: Interact Indoor Navigation Development Engineer

Signify(Philips Lighting)
November 2020 to till now.

Uses Visible Light Communication (VLC) and Bluetooth-Low-Energy (BLE) to locate the mobile devices inside the building with less than 30cm of accuracy.

Link: Interact Indoor Navigation | Play Store: Interact YellowDot | Youtube Link: https://youtu.be/JyuSeg4HIUk https://youtu.be/ihc49cLm-TM

• Native Android with Kotlin, Jenkins

### Project 2: Interact Retail Install Development Engineer

Signify(Philips Lighting)
October 2020 to till now.

Interact Retail Install app connects "customer sites" to the Interact Retail IoT platform.

Link: Interact Retail Install | Play Store: Interact Retail Install | App Store: Interact Retail Install

• Flutter, Dart, Jenkins

Project 3: Worker Assist

Senior Engineer

Honeywell

January 2020 - Sep 2020

This app is for industrial people which helps to stabilize video/audio communication between fieldworkers and experts. App run's on Realwear headset HMT-1, Android Phone/Tab and iPhone.

Link: <u>Honeywell Forge Workforce Productivity - Worker Assist</u> | Play Store: <u>Honeywell Forge Worker Assist</u> | Youtube Link: <u>https://youtu.be/rtwYSjviYck | https://share.vidyard.com/watch/AC85zXuBBNVk9h6Mw8BRAd?</u>

- Native Android, Java WebRTC(Frozen mountain liveswitch) for video call, Retrofit, Dagger, Crashlytics,
   Gradle's product flavors
- Appium, jMeter, Coverity tool, Azure, JavaScript(by testing, release, backend, and web UI team)

# Project 4: Document Assist(App on Realwear headset HMT-1) Senior Engineer

Honeywell

May 2019 - November 2019

It helps fieldworkers inside the industry to fetch and view various documents on demand.

• Used Android API 29 with Kotlin and Java, Espresso, Junit 4, Volley, Crashlytics, Gradle's product flavors, Appium, Coverity tool, IIS, .Net(by testing, release, backend, and web UI team)

# Project 5: Video Assist(App on Realwear headset HMT-1) Senior Engineer

Honeywell

February 2018 - April 2019

Video Assist app is for industrial people which help to diagnose the devices by watching related videos.

Youtube Link: https://youtu.be/szBmN739P8k

- Used Android API 27 with Java, Google Exo-player to play HLS video (stream and local video)
- Retrofit, Dagger, Amazon LEX, Crashlytics, used Gradle's product flavours
- Appium, jMeter, SonarQube, Azure media services, Angular4(by testing, backend, & web UI team)

### Project 6: DynAMo Alarm Management Metrics and Reporting

Honeywell

Senior Engineer October 2016 - December 2017

This is a system-independent software that collects and stores all alarm and event data, monitors alarm system performance, and diagnoses alarm problems via intuitive reports.

Link: DynAMo Alarm Management

• Web app and enhancement using Kendo UI and jQuery, Visual Studio with ASP.NET MVC, Window 7

Project 7: LivingTree
Senior Engineer

Tata Elxsi Pvt. Ltd. March 2015 - June 2016 This will allow us to take a leap forward in community building by providing us with our own private social network for collaboration and engagement across our district, school, and classroom communities.

Website: LivingTree | Play Store: Livingtree Engage | Youtube: Livingtree

- Used Native Android with Java, Android Studio, GCM, Volley, Crashlytics, Bitbucket, and Github
- App authentication through Google and Facebook, PHP, MySql, AWS(by backend team)

### Project 8: Call Statistics for SIP call Senior Engineer

Tata Elxsi Pvt. Ltd. February 2015 - March 2015

Show's call statistics and the amount of data transfer when a call is made or received by the user.

- Developed Complete Android Application.
- Used AchartEngine to show call statistics and android SIP call API.

# Project 9: PWD Progress Monitoring System(CPWD, Karnataka) Senior Development Engineer

Pixel Softek Pvt. Ltd. April 2014 - December 2014

Allows the contractor to upload captured photos of the worksite, GPS Location, and some other fields.

Website: 1. http://103.241.144.46:81/ 2. http://49.206.241.178:8082/

- Developed Complete Android Application using Eclipse, GCM, JSON, SQLite, SVN, Location Manager
- Struts 2, Tomcat 7, Oracle, MyEclipse(used by backend team)

### Project 10: MORTH, India Senior Development Engineer

Pixel Softek Pvt. Ltd. December 2013 to March 2014

Collects device location and other data when an accident happens on the road. Use Google map to ping the location.

- Complete Android Application using Eclipse, SQLite, Google Map V2, Google Place, GCM, JSON
- Developed a server-side application using J2EE, Struts, Postgre Database, Hibernate, tomcat.

# Project 11: BBMP Pothole Monitoring System Development Engineer

Pixel Softek Pvt. Ltd. January 2013 - November 2013

The android application helps to capture pothole photos and other information and sends it to the BBMP server. Users can see the status of reported potholes on Google map.

- Complete Android app using Eclipse, SQLite, Google Map V2, Google Place, GCM, JSON, canvas
- Developed a server-side application using J2EE, Struts, Postgre Database, Hibernate, tomcat.

# Project 12: KRWSSA(Online Monitoring System) Development Engineer

Pixel Softek Pvt. Ltd. March 2012 - October 2012

Android app which helps to generate/keep a record of improved quality of rural water supply and sanitation service delivery for Karnataka Rural Water Supply and Sanitation Agency (KRWSSA).

- Complete Android app using Eclipse, SQLite, JSON.
- Developed a server-side application using J2EE, JDBC, Postgre Database, and tomcat.

#### Project 13: m-POS(Envids, Bangalore, Karnataka, India)

Freelancing October 2012 - May 2013

Android application that reads the barcode of the product. The salesperson uses this application to sell the product after reading the barcode of the product which customers want to buy. She/he suggests the customer buy a product depending on the selection of one product. This app also generates a final bill with a barcode for each product on the bill & the bill gets printed by a printer which is connected by this application through Bluetooth.

- Complete Android app using Eclipse, SQLite, JSON.
- Developed a server-side application using J2EE, JDBC, Postgre Database, and tomcat.